all right everybody we are back
it is jack murphy this is the jack
murphy live podcast
you can find me on twitter at jack
murphy live the website is
jackmurphylive.com
youtube jack murphy live jack murphy
live everywhere the book is democrat to
deplorable
check that out on amazon and if you're
into masculinity
sovereignty and brotherhood check out
the liminal order at liminal hyphen
order dot com today
i have a very exciting and interesting
guest some would say controversial
i'll say informative interesting curious
all kinds of things i have the one and
only professor alexander dugan how are
you doing today sir
thank you thank you how do you look i'm
doing very well i really appreciate you
coming on
uh alexander dugan is a philosopher and
an activist a professor a teacher a
writer a speaker
he's written countless books on politics
and philosophy including including the
fourth
political theory and foundations of
geopolitics we're going to talk about
all that and some more
but the first thing i wanted to talk
about today uh is modernity
um i have been doing quite a bit of
reading
on you and your views on traditionalism
and modernity and all sorts of things
related to that so i would like to start
off if you could define for us
what modernity is and also
give us a bit of a critique if you have
one
so first of all we need to understand
the modernity
not as the um only
a problem of time or something that is
contemporary so modernity is not
exactly or that coincides
with time we live in that is a
shape of very special culture and
civilization
and as such it could belong somehow to
different period of time
so there is a pattern algorithm that is
modernity
and the modernity started in
western europe with the end of the
middle ages
or and after the uh transitional period
of renaissance
that was the beginning of appearance of
manifestation
of some special kind of civilization
with principles that we could
define and understand outside of the
time out so that is in form
and we could compare the problem is how
to
to to define the modernity with what
exactly
uh do we need com con uh compare
the modernity and there is the the main
leading uh leading suggestion let us
compare to
in order to understand the modernity
with tradition or segregate so
modernity is anthony's something
completely completely uh opposite
uh contrary to the sacred traditional
civilization
and we compare two kind of civilization
not necessarily for example christian
uh civilization of the middle age
we could compare the modernity with
islamic civilization we could compare
the modernity
with indian civilization chinese
civilization
to traditional ethnic cults
everywhere outside everywhere outside of
the modernity
we find immediately the sacred
put in the center not necessarily god
not necessarily monophase but always
there is
vertical dimension of the sacred of the
other
other side uh or some transparency
very special kind of transcendence
depending on civilization
but the modernity wanted to destroy
any kind of transcendency uh
transcendence
any kind of sacredness so that was
disenchantment of the world
so a kind of idea invitation or
insistence or imposition
to regard everything that belongs
or belongs to the eternity to the
verticality
as something inexistent so that was a
kind of tyranny of the time tyranny of
the becoming
against the eternity and that was
total reversal of the uh
all kinds of values accepted as
basic in the world of tradition of
religion
of archivism in every sense so
exactly is there a universality in
traditionalism you make a comparison
between modernity and traditional where
traditional has the sacred
at the center and then you say that the
chinese
civilization indian civilizations uh
have sacred at the center is there a
commonality
in traditionalism or is there variety
interesting interesting point when we
are uh
thinking only in the terms of the
christianity
of the western western christianity we
are obliged to compare
the modernity with christianity but when
we uh get deeper in the essence the very
nature
of the modernity we understand that
modernity is not
a choice other from christianity
but that is the choice outside of
all kind of the sacred traditions uh but
these traditions
can be very very uh very different
uh uh between uh uh each of them so
the concept of tradition appears
manifests when modernity arrive
so we could it is very difficult to
speak about universality of tradition
uh when there is uh nothing except the
tradition so there is
there could not be no traditionalism
outside of the modernity modernity gives
us the point of view to understand
what is universal and common uh
to all the traditions but outside of
modernity
we remark oh that is islamic version so
it is
incompatible with christian revision of
holy trinity oh there is chinese version
is this incompatible
with monotheistic uh vision oh there is
india
and so on but when modernity arrives
as a kind of radical and absolute
negation
of the tradition the concept of
tradition
appears in all its glory i would say
so we could get to the universality of
the secret
only with the negative help of modernity
so modernity
reveals uh as absolute evil in my
opinion how uh beautiful
how happy how profound and enrich
all tradition any tradition is not only
our
for example any tradition so anything
that predates modernity anything that
modernity
allows us to reflect back upon is there
a
competition amongst traditional
civilizations or traditional viewpoints
or perspectives
are they compatible do they compete
is one more successful is one bring you
more happiness or joy or whatever the
goal may be
so first of all when we put modernity
outside for example if we um discard
modernity we imagine that
there is no modernity immediately we
will uh
we will observe and remark first of all
the competition
so a kind of competitions kind of
hostility um
a hat rate maybe between different kind
of tradition
but when modernity is here it
shows us how secondary are
all these inner contradictions
inside of tradition because modernity
gives us
common denominator because uh modernity
uh negates all kind of tradition it is
not only
against christianity not only against
monopolies
it is against all kind of tradition
politistic monetistic
and that uh uh transform our
our proper understanding of what is
tradition
and the second point you have mentioned
so it is not the
kind of uh invitation to go to go back
uh to in the in the time before
modernity
has arrived because modernity is a form
we could regard the modernity as an
island
around this island there is tradition
and not only in time
in space for example whereas when we are
speaking about the
uh east and the west modernity is the
modernity in the west and outside in the
same time
in the same physical time material
time there could exist and there exist
a tradition exist tradition outside so
there is a form
that is very important thing so
tradition it is not
necessarily past comparing with western
modernity
it is the past but comparing for example
with a present day of
islamic civilization for example or uh
traditional civilization of people of
africa
or with hinduism it is not
uh that that doesn't mean that
it is the past it could be
uh present it could be future as well so
modernity is an option
it is not kind of fatality that was the
option of the western civilization in
the certain moment
when the western man has decided
to go that way but that doesn't mean
that there is no
other way there is a decision that was a
choice
and we are under influence of this
choice and now we are coming to the
end the final result of this choice
i think that was a wrong choice but we
could prove that test that only when we
are coming to the
the utmost results and consequences of
this choice we will see now we are in
in front of the last judgment last
judgment
of the modernity whether it
it was good or way or it was the
the the way to the at this i am
absolutely sure
being traditionalist being christian
being conservative that that
was and that is the way to the abyss
but it will be reveals uh my opinion
it's my opinion it's our opinion of
conservative
part of the humanity but we will see all
of us
will get the final proof okay we are
definitely living uh
in that moment right now so my
assumption
uh from your reading and from what you
said is that perhaps america is
manifestation of modernity
is that is that right at this point in
time like current
america is sort of the genesis of
modernity
stemming from as you say the renaissance
through the enlightenment
into you know the migration to north
america and the creation of the united
states
that this is a manifestation of
modernity today is it the founding is it
is it america as it stands uh
where does modernity come in the context
of the united states
uh first of all i divide i separate
united states from the other america
the spanish america was not so
uh um identical with
the modernity that was continuation of
the middle ages of the latin
catholic middle ages outside of european
continent
the real cut of the roots was precisely
with
northern america with united states they
uh this structure was
was born with the modernity but
interesting so that was in avant-garde
of
modernity the the american society was
based precisely on protestantism or on
the
uh rationalism on the pragmatism on
materialism in some way and the power of
america
is power of modernity it is not the
power of tradition
the power of of uh beauty it is the
power of material
material force or money
industry technology development
progress so that is we could not uh
hardly we could separate from american
image
all this material greatness so the
greatness of
a post-european uh modern society but
what so generally speaking you're right
so
america uh has born with uh was born
was born with uh modernity
but today we are uh
we have gone too deep in the modernity
and we when we compare the the
principles
of north american society with
the new norm of the time of this
uh uh uh uh time that has
uh lost any kind any relation to
eternity so this is
totally free time uh liberated time this
time
is very it is destruction radical
destruction
and when we compare this new
version of modernity
a kind of post-modernity or contemporary
state of development of modernity with
american identity
we could remark that it is not so easy
because
now the new conflict is the old
modernity that represented by
some parts of american society with new
modernity
and i think that is precisely what we
have now in the
uh electoral campaign there are two
americas two united states of america
one belongs to the
early modernity with liberalism with
guns
with some individualism
and some dignity of the human person
that
defends and defines his
or her own understanding and that was
granted
by the founding father in the beginning
comparing maybe to the sakura tradition
it is
modern but comparing with new turn
of the modernity with this new modernity
comparing with all modernity
is already something obsolete uh
according to
these representatives of new modernity
so new modernity updated modernity they
destroy human dignity totally destroy
uh gender identity human identity and
tries to replace the human by robots by
um artificial intelligence it is
already some development that
uh obliges us to revise our
attitudes to america and that was with
trump when trump came to the power that
was shocked
so that was show half of american
population has
voted against new modernity
and defended uh old modernity
that is the very important i think um
on the level of the civilization of the
world history
very important sign and we could not be
blind to that
we should understand that now maybe
your fight or a fight in america between
all modernity
and new modernity is more important
than everything else if you uh if you
can
win if you can uh at least to stop
uh including for time being this
eschatological eschatological process to
falling down into a beast
that is biden hillary uh globalist
abyss so you will be catacomb you will
be
keeper of the order you will be saver
so old modernity came
by the paradox and the dialectic of the
history
to our side to the side of
traditionalism so that
sure that is very important observation
because
it changes many things regarding america
so
i i i said surely i have revived my
geopolitical position so
i see geopolitics not only ex
external relations of uh heartland of
russia
against atlanticism i see the same
heartland in
america republican states in the
heartland of american continent
and i see a coastal the maritime
sea power on the coasts of
america represented by the so-called
blue states
so liberal geopolitics is something
inner and not uh only external so very
very interesting so very interesting and
i think that there's a lot of things
that you said there that we can find
common ground
on which would be to say that the modern
incarnation of american politics with
its erasure of gender
and and and the erasure of the
individual which to me is a big deal but
i think
according to what i've read from you the
individual it's not
uh high up on your list of priorities we
can talk about that in a minute
but it is uh you echo certainly the
feeling that many of us have in the
united states that
there is a competition between sort of a
degrading
society and culture that has no god and
no family
and no nation versus one that does
does value uh family community
nation and god and we're seeing that
play out and i would think
i've done a lot of reading on uh
pre-founding
uh sort of religious sermons in the
united states and in the in the 18th
century before the declaration
and uh it's clear that at that time in
the united states there were
there were very extreme traditionalists
and very extremely spiritual and
religious people that came to united
states to have the freedom to express
those religious ideas and their version
of uh spirituality
and uh even to the extent that some of
the settlers believed that they were
founding a new israel they were zionists
they were here to to form the the new
grand kingdom
and america was founded as far as i can
interpret it on a notion that
there needs to be no intermediary
between god and the people
uh previous civilizations that had uh
the
the king uh between god and the people
or
the church between god and the people
but here in the united states i think
that we were looking towards a direct
connection to god
as a continuation of the reformation
perhaps
and to me that that creates a special
sort of
spirituality that may not have been seen
elsewhere
do you have any comments or thoughts on
that element of american tradition
so uh it's difficult to judge to me
i have searched in the beginning of the
reformation
and uh it was a very interesting point
that
uh before the reformation the
there were a kind of criticism of
catholicism in europe from precisely
mystical point of view
as weekly as uh ray
reigns mystics as eckhart
soy souza or
so and they were uh very they have they
they have
had very huge impact on luther and
information
that was precisely demand to direct
relations between
man and god outside uh beyond all kind
of
intermediarity so and that was a kind of
right
aspect of our reformation but trying to
establish this
direct link to god uh
and as long as i i understand that uh
the
traditional uh collective uh identity of
the church
was split in and destroyed so uh that
the demand
of the direct relation relation was very
legitimate
and the criticism of degrading catalysis
was as well
legitimate but the result above always
calvinism and some other
there was much more devastating than
creative so
that was the kind of balance inside of
protestantism
for example i i like very much uh jakub
boom and
geek so protestants mystics
and so uh some of aspect we are
really very very spiritually interesting
but as well there were
there there were many form of
in my at my opinion of perversions of
this
christian spiritual relation but what
you have said about individualism very
interesting very interesting because
from the point
of uh of mystical tradition
individual is the last last
stage the external man and there is
internal man inner man
and inner most men as well that is
hidden
and the individual can be good when he
is linked to something that is supra
individual inside of him
not outside inside so there is a very
deep dimension that secures
to individuality the the real value the
value of
expression on something more of the
inner uh freedom but when you cut
this tie between individual
and its core and hidden center
so individual uh loses uh
individuality loses this spiritual
relation
and very vulnerable from this time and
it could to be uh turn uh it it could
turn uh into the individual
individuality divisibility
divisibility so and in that moment when
individual loses its sacred
dimension so it becomes
opposite and that is individual is good
individuals
individualism is bad i think so this
kind of uh
exterior uh uh individualism
and when we have today so now
uh because there is no uh
inner support for a spiritual
individuality
for for family for uh
religion in the individualistic liberal
society
the globalists they they play on that
and that's absence of the foundation of
the ground
for this individuality and they try to
transform
this individuality into the path to cut
it
and to recomb make recombination that is
the post-humanism
already so individualism now uh
is a kind of victim of posthumanism
before uh it could be regarded as
middle position between affirmation of
the inner dignity of the inner man
and uh external man he was on the border
on the on the frontier
but when the the the the center
of the perversion of the mystery of
iniquity
has changed its position uh in front of
the human personality
now it is outside it is pure materialism
is
uh techno science it is the idea to
transform
uh individual in the pure program
in a pure algorithm so that is
artificial intelligence that is cyber
and that
will be the next logical
stage of destruction of the humanity
today they destroy
the gender they destroy the human uh
belongingness to
to the sexes to to family and tomorrow
they will destroy the last
last stage of collective identity the
humanness
so they will defend post human
individual so
it will be not individual at all so that
is precisely in the center so
individualism
comparing with the full-scale
tradition it is not not the value it is
it is something exterior not important
but
now it obtains more and more uh
importance because
now the globalists are going to destroy
individualism so it is as in case with
early modernity of united states it
becomes
our last last uh
fortress uh to to to defend so
uh because when we uh perceive that we
are going
to lose human individuality so
we we understand that we need to to
fight for total to save it
but my idea in order to fight individual
we need to save god we need to reverse
this atheist materialist version
and to defend sacred tradition where
individual can have the the real ground
and the real uh real help from the
transcendence
our without transcendence we could not
accomplish our mission
from from my reading and from my
discussions with millerman
uh and in in fourth political theory and
you outline
uh the you know fascism communism
liberalism and you reject
elements from each and take some from
each as well
my understanding is that in liberalism
your rejection is of the individual
of individualism but you take from it a
sense of freedom
and i was confused there because here in
america you know we say
freedom first thing you think of is
individual right like my individual
ability to be free and to do what i want
but if individualism is a is at once
rejected
um but i'm hearing you also say uh that
we want to sort of defend the
destruction of the individual
from technology and from modernity so
i'm a little bit confused there it seems
to be
maybe a misunderstanding but a little
bit of a contradiction because
if i understood your pre-trump positions
on america and american liberalism is
that
it needs to be destroyed right that it
was it's leading us to the abyss
but at the same time now it feels like
there's some element
of a defense there for the individual um
could you help me
understand that am i not understanding
that exactly right or
so america is not the only uh
only society where or where you could
speak and the first political theory is
much more general so it is not destined
for american public
if americans want to read it or publish
or discuss or reject on debate
it's uh it's very well nice and i am
open to that
but i consider liberalism um
as the process of destruction of
collective identity and collective
identity is not only
a material some
summary of many individuals i don't con
i don't think that man is individual i
think the man
is spiritual being the man is the
mystery
and individual is the external form of
it
so uh when we uh uh
uh recognize the sacred root of
individual
we should defend precisely the man the
man
and the freedom because i think that
individual
to an individual is could not be the
subject of the real freedom
real freedom is uh much more in
the depth so individual is a kind of
external
shape and when we
deny the internal essence
what that is the real subject it should
be a real subject of freedom
we pervert the the main the
the the meaning of freedom and that
exactly
what has happened with liberalism
it started as defense of the freedom and
at the end with the today newly liberals
modern liberalism with democrats
it is total destruction of any kind of
freedom so
you are obliged to be liberal you you
you are obliged to follow this liberal
agenda
and if you decline if you uh uh
uh diverge if you get a one step out
outside you are immediately targeted
you are deplotformed cancelled and uh
and uh
demonized as uh stalinist nazi
uh toxic masculinity
patriarchality and so on so uh that
but that is not something that is
opposite uh contrary to liberalism it is
the logical end
when you uh miss uh
the subject the real subject of the
freedom
of uh with this inner core was that was
the image of god in us
uh that is free but our individuality
uh is can be free and can be
totally totally manipulated from outside
so
i think that is not something taken for
granted
uh the freedom it's we should fight uh
for that affirming our inner dignity
and liberalism becomes more and more
something quite opposite
so you should imitate the political
elite of so-called progressists
and follow their agenda uh letter to
letter
and if you diverge so immediately you
you are done
so that is uh a kind of
manifestation of the real agenda of the
liberalism
so of the individuality so in my opinion
we need to to to
put aside or deconstruct individual
as a in liberal political theory but
not in favor of class or communism or
nation we need reaffirm completely new
uh a new understanding of the human
nature and
i i find this re redefinition in
heidegger in his
uh being their design it is existential
basis so design is neither individual
nor collective nor racial nor ethnical
it is something other it uh is
located in the essence of the
being of a human so it is not easy to
to grasp it and it demands some effort
and in order to construct for political
theory
we should overcome all this metaphysical
superstructure
individuality class society
or at nos or a nationality or state
because the the real nature of of the
men
is otherwise as elsewhere and to find it
to reaffirm that with some
philosophical methodology not basing on
vague presumption intuitions and so on
we have some method phenomenological
methods
method we have hydrogen method we have
as well uh traditionalism of julius
evola renegadon
that affirms the inner man so we need to
say
first of all inner man inner man and not
ext external man is the is the inner man
universal or do all of us have the same
inner man
interesting point uh in my opinion no
or or better we don't know that and we
never
will uh know that before we try
so that is open question let us become
the real americans
let us become the real russians let us
become the real muslims
let us become inner chinese
who is chinese american russian and
muslim and we will see finally
only at the end of this journey to
our depths could be revealed
is there is man universal or not
so i am in favor of multiplicity
plurality of designs
maybe maybe we will discover some kind
something universal but we shouldn't
start with
uh such affirmation just because when we
start
affirming that uh we know or
or universality of the human is taken
for granted for
us that only means that we consider we
replace our american understanding of
what is human with universal or russian
or european or muslim and that is
precisely globalization that is
precisely racism
of the liberals because the liberals
think
they are universal but liberal
liberal values are universal they are
not
that is very important so
human uh human rights are not universal
at least before we ask
all type of society what they think
about human
what they think about rights and when we
with calm could compare and translate
what they really have said about what
they can
what they think about uh human and not
only big civilization
not only chinese india and russia we
need to ask
small tribes in amazonian forests what
do you think you are human you are not
the monkey you are a real human
please say us what do you think about
human rights and we should explain
and her not only speak say but her
what they will answer us and only
putting together
and uh trying to recombine
or compare we could arrive to the real
universal human rights concept not when
some group of bill gates and soros
affirm that they know
what human rights are so is there a
universal morality
for example if we go to an amazonian
tribe and
they believe that it's the right thing
to kill everyone over the age of 45
for example and that's how they live
their lives and their cultures and
whatnot
does that does that earn them a seat at
the table for this discussion
as to what you know uh human rights are
or what the individual experiences are
or what a universal morality
is there a universal morality or is it
is it all relative just based on
your civilization or your your group or
where you live
or or where you're from when we are not
ready to speak with all human about
what they think uh is moral
we could not pretend to universality we
are still
in relativism because if we we don't
uh we don't really feel ourselves ready
enough to speak with some archaic
peoples
to to discuss with them what is good and
what is bad
so we just replace what we
think is good uh and impose
that in the colonial racist way on them
so there is no dialogue so that is uh
uh precisely what liberals uh say so we
now
we conservative we are in the position
of these
poor amazonian tribe people so
they say you believe in god but there's
a prejudice
that that is stupid you shouldn't you
should believe in the progress and the
technical development
development you you go to the church oh
how stupid it is
so you are underdeveloped white million
cannibals
male cannibals and you should be uh for
the peace and the sake of them progress
and of universality to be
um isolated from that so they treat us
exactly
last week we would like to treat
amazonian tribes so i
from my opinion we need to accept all
humans with all their cultures
to dialogue not to to to to be
to imitate them immediately for example
to to eat
our elders and the breakfast i i
it will be anti-christian that doesn't
fit us
uh but if we say oh you are stupid pigs
murderers criminals your uh your
your treat your elders or your children
in that way
so we are in the position of liberals so
let
us then to to continue we need to be
clear and sincere
in our in our principles so i think we
could arrive
to the universality only only
by affirmation of our own particularity
of our church our tradition our roots
and by this way closing more and more to
the center to the innermost
core of our own identity
we could maybe arrive to the point to
understand
the deep identity of the other because
judging from outside it is not correct
so we need but in order to judge from
inside
we need to to to turn into into the
indians or into the russians
or into into the chinese so
um my idea that we need to overcome
the racism in all its form so
we are different cultures are different
people are
different um identities are different
but we could not establish the real
hierarchy among them because that will
be
uh unjust we just will put on the top
around identity oh how good is to be
russian and
all the americans or all the europeans
all the muslim fellow chinese
are worse than us that is racism that i
hate in my own people in my culture
so i think that uh racism has nothing to
do with the
legitimate defense of the deep identity
so i
i love my people i i i consider and
respect
all the uh all the other people but i
could not affirm
that our people is better than a any
other it's my people i will die for it
but i will defend its identity but i
could not say
it's better but it is impossible to say
it's in
i unscientifical in a
in a multi-polar universe in a
multi-polar
world is that not an inherently
competitive world that then
establishes a hierarchy this is
what i'm interested in one angle is if
you have
multiple areas of influence multiple
civilizations respecting their inner
selves expressing their own
values and identities and their own
version of the sacred
um if there's multiple of them existing
are they not
in a competition are they not forming
naturally a hierarchy do we not see this
in nature as well i think that is a kind
of open open open issue for example if
we consider
pre-columbian pre-columbian world
that was multi-polar world pre-columbian
with chinese empire indian state
uh iranian empire persian empire arab
empire
russian empire turkish empire after that
after arab arabic uh um european empire
uh and aztec empire
incas empire so the people uh
lived in this civilization
each of this civilization represented
the poll
uh did they compete somehow
did they exterminate themselves not at
all
uh war or peace was the role
no neither war nor peace combination
so competition hierarchy i don't think
so
because uh every christians so they were
much
higher than than oh oh the rest but the
chinese
on their part they saw they are much
higher than
than india and or or the european so
the hierarchy can be kind of
ethnocentric illusion and has such uh
status uh in in that multi-polarity
uh i don't think that when we are
dealing with the
diversity that leads to
extermination war sometimes
yes sometimes no but when we are living
in the liberal world we have the war we
have the destruction of intervention we
have
uh the uh humanitarian bomberman
we had uh last century to
a huge world war precisely
with democracy liberalism so i don't
think
that uh globalism
uh save us
us from the destruction
from wars but we need to put the
peace in the war in the natural limits
so we should establish a kind of water
of the respect
of some rules based on power so that is
why
each civilization should have some
serious weapon in order to defend
its sovereignty and independence
so hierarchy based on power
no not the necessary hierarchy
independence
based on self-defense independence and
sovereignty
based on self-defense and not necessary
hierarchy
for example uh i i don't think that
civilization has these
uh self-destruct
inside of it it could be a
hierarchy leads to some uh
univocal uh submission of
uh parts of the people and the
top position of the other this hierarchy
when whether it is based on the
pure power it is bad but when a
hierarchy is based on the heroes uh
on the sacredness on the philosophical
metaphysical
position it's not necessary that it will
lead
to such physical uh physical oppression
or physical competition so i think i'm
in that sense platonist
i think that philosophers should rule
and philosophers
will understand better where when
it's time to go to war and when it's
time
to stop and plato's gave us very
beautiful example
how important is to combine philosopher
and warrior warrior because warrior is
uh self-destruction and his his
will to to establish hierarchy to or
competition
is destruction but philosopher is not
enough
he is too good uh plato says
he he is too good he is too kind he
he will destroy its own uh its own
society be
with that kindness so we need a mixture
between
uh uh serious intellectual philosopher
and brave warrior that that is this
combination
is necessary to balance the the peace
and war and to put the war in the just
limits
and to revive uh the pure
philosophical intellectuality with some
passion
for your passion so we need to accept
both the thinker and the warriors
in the organic and
balanced uh proportions let's play
platonic right man
there's a lot there's a lot there it's
so many so many questions i could ask
but i'm gonna move things along just a
little bit here you said that when
trump was elected that changed
everything from your perspective
and i would like to maybe point out that
prior to that uh you
uh i had read had called for uh to
support
anybody that was against american
liberalism
uh whether it's fostering racial
divides within the united states or
or egging on other dissident factors or
anything else within the united states
that might lead to the end of this
liberal hegemony but now you've said
that since trump was elected
that changed everything for you can you
explain
what your how you're thinking may have
changed since trump was elected and
and would you still call for uh
supporting those same divisive elements
within the united states black lives
matter
anti-anti-fascist antifa uh anarchist
etc you know what changed and
and how would your prescription change
first of all my idea to to
to help uh with all our means
to destabilize or united states of
america
these words were written in the
beginning in the 90s
and the beginning of the 2000 when
when american society seemed
to be very very
consolidated totally devoted
to globalism and or when the change
between republicans and democrats
changed
anything at all didn't change anything
at all
so that was the same the same the same
uh strategy the same values the same
uh globalism right or left but with the
same
consequences so that was analysis and
these global globalist united states of
america
hugely attacked russia
in order to to destroy to for example
that
just just now this support for for the
navalny who is nobody
zero zero person but all the west
supports navalny with no no support
inside of our our country we have many
criticism against putin now
and that is growing but nawali has
nothing to do with that
he is totally outside of any political
agenda
but when the west was so uh
so big voice vehemently tries to support
some zero that is intrusion
that is intervention in our inner
politics
and how stop it let's try strike back
let's recon the enemy who
who maybe who is not the enemy but what
who behaves
himself or herself as enemy should be
considered
enemy finally so nothing personal i
would say
and uh all this reaction of the west or
united states during 90s when we had
yeltsin
trying to demonize more and more
supporting chechen
and separatists everything against
against russia
against our our identity our sovereignty
and i have applied this
uh and the tactic of the of the west
supporting their network or american
network inside of russia with all means
with political
economical cultural power to destabilize
destabilizing
elements the only way to do the same and
i
think including in your situation
you you should understand that that was
logical
at least if you are aggressed strike
back otherwise you will be killed just
killed and controlled and
uh but when trump came to power
we had we had a proof not just sentiment
failing sympathy or some inclination on
intuition
we had the proof that half of american
society
is radically against this
interventionist
globalist liberal agenda so that was the
very important sign
so i i has a
rethought i have revised my attitude
i would say i i all my sympathy
is on the side american people defending
its identity against these uh
chaos that is ruling now i'm not
happy at all it could seem
that um it could seem that my provision
uh uh are fulfilled now
because if you compare what i have
written uh
30 years ago what i would wish in
america
happen that is happening now precisely
but
it it has arrived but i am not happy
i i rather feel a solidarity
with traditional american
white black spanish all kind of real
normal people defending your
values your traditions your principles
in including when i'm not so much
uh fond of them so that is up to you
to love your your history
your heroes it is maybe for myself they
are not so much hero
but i respect and i am
deeply involved morally and emotionally
with your fight to save your country
from the hand
of the people that will bury it so
i i'm absolutely sure if if biden
wins there will be no united states
maybe
for multi-polarity it's not so bad but
it is immoral
immoral because i see the real people
the real society the people very close
to psychologically to myself fighting
today for the dignity for
the uh morality for the family for
for identity so uh uh democrats
tries to try to destroy
totally american identity including
philosophically
culturally they tried to change to
develop so-called to
to put the american society in the
progress but
what they uh get they get only
destruction
coyote uh robberies so murder
so they they they receive the quite
opposite results it is not development
it is pure degradation so they destroy
america and i could confess i am not
happy at all
and all my solidarity in spite of
geopolitical tensions in spite of my
disagreement with uh including with
trump's
concerning iran china i'm not i'm not at
all
uh in agreement with that i i it's
to to me it's error but i my soul
is with american people american society
not such so much with trump because it
is
uh beyond trump already it's it is much
more important
and uh when i see the this small small
young guy standing in front of the
of the crazy mop of so-called democrats
defending some monuments of of on in the
south
i almost i almost cried so he was
he defended my position so i could
and i wish to be in his post to
defending
my heroes my identity against
this demonic absolutely destructive
uh crowd and that doesn't mean that i
i'm
uh very happy with american history or
slavery i i don't like slavery
absolutely
absolutely as as north americans by the
way
as you're the serious part of you
and you fought against that so uh we
need to
to put everything in the uh correct uh
historical
historical position and i i would not
uh blame the black people for example
african-american absolutely they are
victims
but they should try the way to establish
their our identity to
to promote their our legitimate rights
in not to be uh tools
of this uh globalist group that don't
care absolutely about them and about
their values about
their lives that the huge reach
uh billiarders billionaires as
soros white and totally uh
um totally alienated from
american real american life they use
them
in order to to to uh achieve
their murderous goals so i i am totally
on the side of real america and uh
i think that the people who are
protesting they are
used they are manipulated they will be
they are also
victim i wouldn't demonize them i
wouldn't diminish people
the real demonic power it is political
liberal globalist elite
behind them they and they use them and
after that
and they abuse them and they try to to
to split american society and
uh i think that uh it will be immoral
from my conservative traditional point
of view
to to be happy with that
and i am not yeah yeah i think we have
some agreement there for sure
the people protesting the minority
groups black lives matter these
these people are being used especially
the people being used in america right
now are white
middle class women especially who
are just taking these globalist
lies and these identitarian lies and
these racist lies and
absorbing them and feeling guilt and
shame about them and then also
uh permitting and giving consent
basically to
riots and protests and destruction and
voting biden in
uh i agree is is continuing down the
path of degrading
america i'm happy to hear about uh
your evolution in thinking which i
admire and all great thinkers evolve
their their thinking
as things change right like the facts
change things change on the ground and
therefore you have new positions and so
i commend you for that and i appreciate
that
um when you when you speak of an
american culture
that you relate to or an american
tradition that you relate to
or support what does that look like to
you from your perspective
could you describe what an american
traditionalism is or what america is or
what an american
identity is what does it look like to
you
so after after having written the book
on american
identity i have written uh
24 volumes about all on all civilization
that is called no mahia
the war of mind of or the word of
intellects
one of this volume was dedicated to
north uh
american identity and when i started to
to write it i i i had
little sympathy to say the truth with
america as the mother creation of
modernity
when i when i started to read more and
more in-depth
uh uh american writers i i
had i have received very special feeling
that america is a known country
is american culture american identity
is doesn't uh is exactly what everybody
thinks it is as american uh claim to
what means to the america what european
how europeans
understand america or
are we russians so i have discovered
american amer american identity and
in my opinion uh maybe it maybe i'm
wrong
just my opinion my observation that
american identity
is is rooted in the pragmatism
but what is pragmatism it's not anger
sex and
utilitarianism not at all that not about
utility of the things
but that if that is about the action
pragmatism a greek term it is the
action pragma practice
so practice practice uh in
its essence is a kind of application of
metaphysic
metaphysical approach so they could not
be practiced without theory
but if you you you call for the
pragmatism
for activity you could
do that in many ways and you americans
you
do that in in a very very
interesting ontological uh
field you affirm
you are totally free inside of yourself
so there is no prescriptive knowledge
about your subject because you could
pretend
to be everybody you want god elvis
presley mickey mouse
version there is no no law to define
your inner man but as well there is no
no prescriptive knowledge about external
world
so the world is exactly as you like
it to be if uh other if
it's accept that so that is the huge
freedom on both sides of the
uh ontological map you are totally free
inside of yourself you're totally free
outside
of yourselves the only way that limits
you
only think that limits you it is what is
between
that is pragmatism so the pre in the
pragmatism
there is the encounter of meeting point
between
two infinities in inner infinity
of the absolutely undefined
self and outer infinity of the
total possibility of the being and the
meeting point
is it works or it doesn't work that's
all
but that could be that could lead to the
worst
and that could lead to the best in
emerson
in um uh for example
in um your uh toro
thorough in uh in uh as well in
[Music]
the the other main romantics
uh uh american romantics
that has led to the huge and beautiful
description
of the uh of the man and of the reality
that is
a kind of of beauty of beauty of the
freedom on both side
that could be as well uh pierce
that has uh pierce has given to that
philosophical philosophical frame very
great i think
and uh the other maybe
authors have used that for more
practical
purposes but nevertheless that this
freedom
is something that prohibit to prohibit
this uh it is prohibited prohibition of
limitation
that is american mind i think and that
is american tradition
it is very particular there's nothing
common with our or european
but very sympathetic to see the truth
but i see today
that this pragmatic identity based on
absolute freedom
except in the act because when you
imagine yourself
a flying man you try to to apply you
could not so that
it doesn't work so but no it is not
not a problem not to try more so that is
purely american go ahead try more maybe
your rings were badly
made so it is very very sympathetic
feature of the real american mind now
neoliberalism new globalism destroys
precisely this identity
that is much more than only christian
or anglo-saxon prototype that much
much deeper pragmatism it's something
that uh fits uh to pro protestant
freedom in the church in the in the
religion but that is something more
and i think that now uh this pragmatism
pragmatical
identity of american mind and american
american spirit
is in danger because those who represent
america on the world scale are not
absolutely like that
they before i thought they
hated in us our freedom but now with
trump and everything you have now
i see they had it in you so that is
anti-american elite
that is ruling in america it's very
interesting philosophical discovery
so we should not uh identify them
with the american identity the
anti-american they are this
they this they are destroying the the
american identity
not in the wasp not in the sense male
white protestant absolutely no
it is about about the pragmatic
pragmatist identity that is much deeper
and that is totally
that includes all uh all other
uh people coming to america precisely
for this freedom
and uh people from europe from outside
they come to america to this freedom of
the spirit of the freedom and to this
pragmatic uh unprescriptive
uh ontology and graceology i think and
they tried to limit and destroy them
today
i think that there's a lot of common
ground there i think that my audience
people
uh that listen uh would certainly agree
that the globalist uh have
do not have american and american
tradition at heart
and that it is actually very destructive
of that and it's interesting that
they've also marshaled the same forces
that you
suggested 30 years ago to disrupt the
american state they're doing the same
thing now
they're they're riling up our minorities
and creating racial divides specifically
creating divides between men and women
feminism uh versus you know destroying
femininity and masculinity
uh it's interesting that the globalists
the elite
the uh corporate state the uniparty
what was the both the democrats and the
republicans together
from the 90s 80s 90s and onward with
obama especially
uh they're they're doing to us what you
what you
prescribed uh to do to us back uh during
the cold war
and it's effective they are having some
success
at sowing discord and discontent and
disillusion to the point where many
people in the united states believe
that the only logical outcome here is a
divorce a separation
perhaps a civil conflict uh
redistricting
some some major change is afoot because
the conflict
is irreconcilable the global elites the
uniparty the corporate masters the
financiers they
they have a vision that is
irreconcilable with that
of traditional america red america the
trump america today so
that's an interesting interesting
framework for me
to consider uh i'm i'm so many
so many other things uh that i would
like to talk about um one
one thing is how do you see russia
and the united states what do you see is
their relationship
moving forward what is possible
what could happen how could we work
together how could we
de-escalate are we natural partners
what is and what should be the nature of
the relationship between
russia and the united states moving
forward
in 2020 so first of all i think that
uh um we are are not
natural born enemies absolutely that
is that or was the case uh uh
explained and uh
by the historical ideological tendency
we uh are no more uh
a kind of bearer of socialist
thinking i have nothing at all against
some kind of traditional
communitarianism i would say
when the people living in in the the
villages i am absolutely not
in favor of capitalism but today russia
is not is not promoting anti-capitalist
or anti-western
or anti-american
ideology russia is on defensive it's
very important
to say don't understand that we are on
defensive we have received
a huge blow in the 90s with the the
destruction of the
soviet union and we try to recover
and we didn't recover yet fully but we
are going
to to recover and to return
to our regional status of the great
great power inside of eurasia so if
there is no idea to rule
all humanity from the washington that
was the globalist idea
and putting in this rule less and less
purely american values and more and more
some artificial
post-human progress is value without
this
will we have nothing absolutely
nothing against america so if you leave
us
in peace if you don't impose on us
uh your agenda and now we see that is
not
your agenda at all it's very important
if you
don't if you don't impose on us
agenda of these crazy globalists that
are destroying today america
so we have absolutely nothing against
your leadership your greatness your
the prosperity so we have
very small small grounds to compete
but if okay if we have something
or somewhere to compete let us compete
so no problem with
all that but there are no
uh some territorial uh pretensions
or some debates on the influence we
could easily
rearrange our geopolitical position
basing on the realism
in all part of the world with no problem
so that is my opinion
so we are on defensive and we are
presented as aggressive
new imperialist greedy
uh russian bear that tries to destroy
all the humanity
but that is globalist lie it is
anti-anti-american
attitude because we maybe we are not the
friends
but we are certainly not the enemies
that is very important
so maybe we are not the saviors we but
with just
nothing nothing to to to suggest
you accept what you choose
to to be so we are a little bit
overestimated uh as evil we are not
global evil
we just russian and i i i
i think to put us in in the normal under
normality
uh it will be much better and much more
useful than to
to continue to to make the kind of uh
absolute evil where it is not and try
i think basing on intuition
understand that very well i will stephen
bannon understand that very well
bannon has different ideological frame
for that
uh thinking speaking about um
christianity judeo christianity other
things but
trump uh feels that there is no danger
for all from us there is
real knowledge we didn't help him we
didn't
support him he is we are not too much
lucky with him
we we had some confrontation during his
rule well not like at all
with this with trump he didn't
accomplish what he
promised to american people and we are
some
how skeptical but that is
normal realistic relation to russia
russia is russia
it's maybe not the friend but certainly
not the main enemy so that is position
of trump
and i think we will be very satisfied
with that
let take us um as we are
so and we will help you we will
realistically think
where you have you need really help and
when
you maybe we will not help you
maybe we will so that is that depends on
many
uh circumstances but the russia is other
it's we could not apply to russia
american
values but today these values or
measures
come i will put on the question in your
country as well so
with trump i think if he wins
and i hope he wins and i wish he he he
he wins uh and uh we
we will be on the same turn not too
friendly not too close
disputing some issues maybe confronting
in
some uh in some uh territories
but we will not come to the war with
this crazy
uh crazy maniac biden who
seems to be quiet and old and
totally incompetent but he is the front
figure
of very very uh toxic
and very aggressive groups by himself he
has nobody i think he's just
american old man old guy and uh
behind him there is the abyss
hidden so and that if he wins
uh i i think that the war could be
possible he continues this
democrats demonization of putin of
russia
all all will be put in the wrong light
uh uh fake news from liberal
mass media will well uh orientated uh
uh at uh and aimed to demonize more and
more russia
and you finally america will believe in
this
wrong image so if you need a friend you
will receive the friends
for if you need sorry um the enemy you
will receive the enemy
if you want to go war with someone
somehow
you could create you could imagine shape
it
so uh if you
if you have a real strong will to start
the atomic war
you could get it outside of we would
avoid it at any price
at any price except the total submission
to our globalists
that is the only way we could not accept
all other
uh price we are ready uh to pay in order
to avoid that
but i i i fear with this
crazy maniacs as uh
globalists we could be obliged to accept
the this suicidal uh
uh challenge so i think uh
uh this is up to you americans to to to
save the world now
if trump is not the savior but he is not
the the the uh the killer
of of the humanity he is just he gives
us
the the time to to respire to breath
with him we could breath without him i
think we
will be not able to breathe so i
breathe it is about biden not about uh
some policemen so uh we can't uh we
can't breath
with globalists still continuing to
define our our
our uh our our life and that is why i
think
uh you need to to stay strong because
they could
they could try the democrats could try
to steal
the elections they they could that so
they already have
uh affirmed i have written that they
will not
recognize the victory of the tr of trump
they have called already just before
election
that it is a fraud election fraud
it is already committed in their uh
their
uh disdain for the reality check
they already affirm russia has already
intervened
interven intervened uh in in favor of
trump
russia already has stolen the election
and they
don't recognize this electoral fraud
just before elections uh begin so
uh and i think that maybe there will be
no
um absolute peace and friendship
and happiness and happy marriage between
russia and united states
if trump wins but if he
will not that caught men's
destruction of humanity because the
danger
is in on your side today
so you are dealing not only with
coronavirus you are dealing with
globalism that is
worse than coronavirus that is the kind
of epidemic
and uh you are much more uh uh
um stroke and
much much more um touched with it
than uh and that is symbolic so beware
uh all our uh hope and trust
uh is uh on you or on
on real america american america
uh you spoke of the the globalists
uh already disputing the election in the
united states
they are also fostering and fomenting
public um dissidents and
riots and protests and disobedience and
violence and
burning and looting and killing we've
had
almost i think 35 people get killed just
this summer
in the protests and the riots in the
streets
i have observed some of this myself live
in person
right on the ground and the mobs are
very active
and all of this seems to echo other
popular quote popular uprisings
found around the world a little bit
color revolutions if you're familiar
with this term
it appears as though that the democrats
the globalists are running the same
playbook
in the united states as they may have
run
in other countries uh in europe eastern
europe and around the world do you
see similarities there uh are you
familiar with the color revolution
are you familiar do you see any
parallels between what's happening in
the united states
and what's happened in other countries
in europe
absolutely we have experienced that
colored revolution in ukraine in georgia
in eastern europe recently in belarussia
it's still going on so that is
a kind of uh scenario um
normal scenario it it was elaborated by
jin sharp
uh george soros and there are some
roadmap for that how to organize that so
jin sharp has
written the book that is translated
including in russia
and distributed uh among russian
protesters and liberals
and interesting so uh it is called
uh uh unviolent uh resistance
non-violent resistance but it
supposes that there will be
the confrontation that will there there
will be
uh uh creation of uh false
uh money there we occupation of the
administrative
building and center of decision the so
non-violence it is the fake
name it is the violent colored
revolution
they are differently violent so they
they involve the people who sincerely
believe
it is non-violent but it is absolutely
violent
it is criminal it is terrorist act jim
sharp
was a respectable american
thinker uh political democrat and he
has written this book how to do color
color revolution before we thought
it was against us and that was against
us
because they tried to uh overturn
the uh non-liberal as they call it
non-liberal regimes with that but uh
in order to organize cal revolution
there we need to huge
amount of money to put uh inside
in the uh indirect way to put including
the stones on the streets to keep for
example to
to hire some uh
auto some cars uh
with the stones in order to keep put
them
on the pretext of some restoration some
reconstruction
in some crucial crucial point so
uh that was very planned that is network
warfare
including using the twitter mass media
finance special self-organization and
radical groups
that they are used in in in the moment
of
uh color uh uh color revolution and day
after that they they will be dismissed
as an ukraine for example that or
ukraine they have used
ukraine nazi in order to accomplish this
ukraine
uh and after that they had to solve them
totally nothing at all so
they use all radical extremist group of
of different color and different
different
structure in order to to ferment
precisely
to foster foster uh
rebellion uh kind of mess
and all this tired chaos and after that
they
they will disappear so they are used
just used for the
short time of being and when with we
never thought
uh thought that it could be applied to
united states
what we see what is going on united
states
that is the repetition of american
scenario to overthrow
hostile non-liberal and
anti-american regime and how much
media treat trump are discussion with by
the how biden
has treated trump it's precisely
application of the rule of color
revolution against
this time against the half of america
and that is
incredible so they have used all
these weaponry against us against
pro-russian so-called totalitarian
not so much for american regime so they
used
exactly exactly the same methodology the
same
network warfare against american
president
and half of the population that supports
uh american president that is really
something interesting and i have spoken
with my friend uh he was um
earlier uh a very important figure in
me i-6 in the british
secret services uh dealing with uh um
[Music]
or oriental area with uh
middle east and he has remarked that
regarding now he's retired and he has
changed many of his
previous position he's very in favor of
multiple polarity
he had said to me that when he
observed uh development of the protests
in america he has remarked
the uh the same stones
put in the crucial point of new york on
seattle so that was precisely
precisely a road map of
the color revolution with serious
uh uh investment
of uh wall street for sure
from some oligarchs from some financial
political uh circles so all these
uh all these protests are organized by
democrat
democrats by the democratic party of
united states of america and by
the heart radical hardcore of globalists
that they have they have hijacked
the old not oldest but old american
uh political party now these democrats
they are not
the same democrats as before the their
party is reject
and neo-conservatives they try to hijack
the same
republican party and trump has
uh accepted and invited bolton and have
have received and has
received uh diplo uh
and in the back from or from bolton
uh so that is uh the same group
it is the group of globalists right
globalists
new conservatives left globalists that
now have had hijacked uh hijacked the
democratic party but they are not
americans at all that is
totally alien elements inside of
american elite and they have
uh organized the color revolution
against
their own country that is this that is
the sign
that they don't belong here they don't
belong to the united states they
they are outsiders i think they don't
belong to europe neither to israel
neither to
to russia neither to china they have no
place
they kind of aliens precisely political
aliens political elites
migrated to the virtuality today fake
news universe of
artificial intelligence so they are from
silicon valley
they maybe they are already post-human
a friend of mine is a writer and he
calls them
the bug men and they are definitely that
aliens they are not part of
our american tradition they do not have
america's interests at heart
and you're absolutely right there is a
color revolution ongoing here in the
united states the very same playbook
gene
sharp all the same cast of characters
the same list of to do's the same
goals and the same strategies and my my
friend darren beatty
dr darren beatty and i we talked about
this extensively on a prior podcast as
well audience so if you want to check
that out
it's like two or three podcasts ago um
sir you mentioned
uh a lot of fascinating things of course
but one thing you mentioned was
network warfare and that's something
that i am very interested in
uh i have been studying the evolution of
warfare
first generation second generation third
and now fourth generation warfare
and combine it with our information
technology
social media all of the connectivity
that we have and we
have arrived at a moment of network
warfare
i'm curious to hear your definition of
network warfare
and what you see as the future of
conflict uh and and how that looks from
your perspective
because we we study that and i have an
organization of men
we study fourth generation warfare we
study network warfare network tribalism
uh and we believe that we're uh in a new
era
of conflict that will not be similar to
past conflicts there will not be
trench warfare there will not be people
lining up on other side of the field and
shooting muskets at each other but
rather some new
hybrid evolved small unit
information warfare conflict so could
you tell me
what your perception is of network
warfare
and and how do you see conflict evolving
in the future in our current environment
so first of all i have written the book
on network warfare
and my friends i have started some some
studies here
on the professional level on the expert
level and the
including in some political level so uh
when i i started to speak about that
nobody believed me
they they thought that just just about
about computer games and something like
that and
after that when i have translated some
texts from the beginning of the 90s of
the american military
magazine parameters and some
other texts of american general american
uh generals uh working generals in the
middle of the 90s with definitions of
this
network were fair and so on only after
fighting with the huge huge
misunderstanding
and uh prejudices i have i have managed
to
to attract the attention of our uh
of our military circles to that so uh uh
i
i i i i have written a lot uh
about that and my friends have uh
developed this idea so first of all
um um to understand correctly
uh in the network warfare we need to
understand
what post modernity is so that is very
interesting because if
it is not about technology or the shift
or the balance of one kind of weapon
in favor of the other uh it is not about
that
that is about the the totally uh uh
total change of the ruling paradigm
the paradigm of modern modernity and the
shift to the post-modernity
in the modernity there was the reality
that was in the center so the reality
realism
real weight of real fights
real fighters uh real resources
and everything was uh was based on the
reality check
the quantity uh the
army the heavy heavy weapon
and everything should be
measured with the measures of the
reality
when we come to the post-modernity
post-modernity
ontology changes ontology so
reality is not like it was in the
modernity so reality
is much more much more indefinite much
more evasive so reality
is not uh it used to be
a reality is much closer to virtuality
so the not about the uh organize
and control uh and rule
the behavior of the bodies but much
more about how to control minds
how how to control psyche uh
human psyche and it is not about the
uh battle as such but
about the disposition to battle so to to
influence on the
starting conditions of of the battle so
idea of
network warfare is that the battles
is always lose a loss
or gained before so that depends
on how what what is this disposition
what is preparedness so it is not about
uh the solution is already already
before beforehand so we need
from that point of view uh it is not
about
who has lost and who has gained but how
it is explained how it is exposed
so that is virtuality so the virtuality
is not
only premise to gain the world but is as
well the consequence
if you gain the real war and you
are described to lose the war you are
loser
so that is uh the law of postmodernism
so everything
has shifted from the reality to the
information to media
to the networks and
reality uh is
almost disappeared has almost
disappeared
outside of these these dispositions
of this dispositive uh french word
uh behind behind the words
behind the uh currents uh
uh and ocean of misinformation
disinformation and finally the concept
of
information has changed also
because information without
the some goal to inform
has lost its meaning there is not about
the truth that about
that is about the victory and if
there is no truth and all only victory
that
is really important so yeah so you are
seduced
somehow
and finally you are not lying anymore
because there is no truth if there is no
truth there is no lie
there is only informational war so that
is
post modernity with uh
structural linguistic with gnostological
process
with psychological adaptation of the
sound processes
on these software level
and the hardware level uh doesn't mean
anything
anymore so you could have the big army
the the fighters the brave fighters and
you
will lose before first shot
uh shot or or of the gun or the rifle
so it is uh for drones
using something uh uh unhuman so that is
post
human the shift or migration of the
human warfare to the post-human
warfare from the modern real to the
virtual and
that redesigns that redesigns
the the shape of the wall so what was in
the center
uh is moving to the periphery what was
outside of the world is inside or in the
center
so uh a mass media
network warfare networks social networks
all the information um
economy as well is secondary because if
you could could be very rich but if you
don't
uh control some informational
currents some channels information so
your richness
could not uh of use could not be of use
at all
so that is it is not about the money
that is not about
about the resources the network warfare
it is about
of the control of mental sphere so
mentality it is inside of mentality
finally
so that is uh so no need to to kill each
other if you could
uh get a result without without
uh shooting the other or uh spending
the power and time so that is i think
uh so uh network warfare is
transforming in the epistemological war
on the control of the mind of the brains
of the people
and i think finally it could be
put in the cyborg sphere totally so uh
in in
in in spite uh
or of controlling the body there will be
control
of of the minds in in
embedding the people into some into the
some uh naira naira
naira structure near nera network
or some uh uh artificial intelligence
and these uh artificial intelligence
will be the
new or war or the field of war
totally new so we just in the beginning
in the process of this
migration from the reality to the
brutality but
that explains the main tendencies
in the development of the strategy of
the
uh strategical thought of the
network warfare so i'm following that
and that is precisely
very serious shift so that uh
and the fact in fact that's that is the
end of the traditional war when you
yeah so uh i agree with all of that we
live it we're experiencing it every day
it is part of my job to fight against
some of those forces misinformation
disinformation try to help people make
sense
of the world in a deliberately polluted
information
space that has a bunch of trash and
garbage and misdirection
all thrown in on top of us to try to
confuse and bewilder us
and strip us of our power a question
came to mind
in the old times traditionally a warrior
is a very specific thing
you can look at somebody you're like
that's a warrior and they have certain
virtues and certain
powers what does a warrior look like
today in network warfare in conflict is
there
is there a new version a new archetype
of warrior
in this new world a new avatar of a
warrior what
what is a warrior today if if the old
conflict the old way of settling things
is no longer very interesting i i
thought about many times so
traditional warrior as the
man uh whose
vocation is death and
death it is applied to other
and to himself so that is uh uh
mutual so he is ready to kill
he is ready to die and both that is
relations to death
he is totally the warrior is totally
devoted the
the death is the wife or bride
of a warrior so he is totally
devoted to to one thing and
mutuality to kill and to die
is inside and the center so that is real
marriage with
that and that that is why warriors
should be bri brave and that is why they
risk their life
so nietzsche has said you say
hez nietzsche that the good
goal make
makes the war noble no the good
war makes uh the goal noble
so that is a kind of uh inside
of the real nature of the warrior so
where is not about
the just or uh in just
case the word is about the death and
that is why
we could remark and say oh that is
warrior
because we we feel we see we experience
this special somehow
intimate relation to the death what is
going today
with arrival of network warfare
we have the the type of the covert
warrior he has unilateral
relation uh to to death he kills
but he he is immune he is secure he
kills with drones with buttons
he kills and he is totally safe
he his relations of the death
is to sow death to and not to experience
it he is covert finally he
is uh he is hidden uh outside of the
battlefield
he isn't he that is perversion for the
warrior it is not
a warrior anymore it is not soldier it
is not uh
not army man that is completely
different that
is monster monster that is butcher
who kills and who cannot be killed
because
all the structure of this globalist
so-called
humanist posthumous uh civilization
defends his right to kill impunity
impudently so that is i think the
deep degradation of the relation of the
man
to the death and that means that
relation to the
life is perverted so the covert warrior
who kills as butcher outside
of his uh of his distance
putting the the button
he should be psychologically
perverted he he is monster he is
uh the uh unnatural
human he is miss gabor in german that is
some some something that is born unknow
abnormally
so that is a kind of um
[Music]
that is not human uh uh kind of because
uh to to experience
death it is as well on on the border to
be human or not
it is just very very uh very special
position
it is human but is the the path
the step to something outside of it and
that is very noble i think so to
to be to be it is the heroic heroic it
is
um not calming it is disturbing
terrorism is disturbing where is
disturbing person
but uh uh um
butcher is sick person so it is really
sickness
so i think this shift from the uh
disturbing heurism of warriors
toward this sickness of the butchers
killing outside of the
possibility to be killed that is the
ontological and anthropological
change in that so for example uh hillary
clinton
uh can kill only when she
is outside of uh uh of the distance when
she
is immune when she is safe and she
is killer the real killer but perverted
killer
and i think trump when he will be
challenged
he would he would fight as as the man
so that is interesting he he will fight
he
was aggressive he could kill but he
could die
and they prefer the situation when
you certainly will die and your killer
certainly will not that is outside of
the war
that is extermination that is why i
think that
this ex extermination camp is
realizing today with the globalist
technologists
the technocentric killers and that
changes the nature of the real warrior
and that
perverts the the soul of the soldier
i think well we are losing the soldier
so uh wonderful answer thank you very
much uh
there has traditionally been a balance
between
priests warriors and mercantilists
if the warrior is changing fundamentally
does this
change the priest and the mercantilist
as well
yes but the priest is totally
lost already in the modernity so there
is no place for the
for the priest for the uh sats or those
uh
such total position so the priest we
have
uh we have lost the priest long ago so
modern priests are not anymore the real
priest because they
if they would behave as a real priest
they will be not tolerated by this
democratic society they they should they
should
uh reveal the people the the reality
of the transcendence but in the world
where there is no transcendence
it is impossible so i i don't think that
really
mark mercantilist were the
third functions i think peasant peasant
and the problem that we are losing the
peasantry
the peasants were the more general
third function in the in the european
societies and we are losing
agriculture because agriculture that is
the way of life
it is not about the profit it is not
about
uh products to to eat it is about life
it is about the relations with nature
with their
family where's the animals where's the
wild nature
or uh cultivated nature and that is
way of life that is the image of the man
so
we most of our society were
traditionally peasants
and that was important and when uh
merchants appeared they have
uh marginalized the peasants and that
was already a very
bad turn in their reality uh and
so i think uh the the the merchant is a
kind of abnormality
as for example new warrior so peasant
is the is the health position so why
i think so important now in your your
your fight is the american american
farmers
so farmer it is a kind of
noble creature it belongs to the
traditional normal society farmer
he is responsible he has has
animals has family has church
he lives in com co uh community
it is communitarian uh way of life
he is alone but inside of some community
with personal relations and with gun
that is very
noble and i think i think that is
aristocracy of the peasantry the real
aristocracy the best
example of the human of humankind it is
precisely peasantry
and we have lost as well the priests and
we have lost
the peasantry now we are losing the
soldiers so all
our traditional uh functions of our
society
uh uh is we are losing uh them
so and you know in spite of them
and their places and their place we're
dealing with some
perversions with some degradation there
are no more
the real priests there are some half
priests simulacrum
there are no more uh soldiers there are
no more peasants
and uh what about uh
merchants i think they could be honest
and uh respectful people but not
in the modern economy but it's totally
virtual and based on the fraud
so this financial economy uh
gives no chance no chances to to the
honest
people to to build uh real fortune
dealing with with the honest relations
to the goods
to to to adapt to to to the market
or all that is in the in the hands of
the
some tricksters or some uh people who
has usurped has uh privatized
uh the um the economy
the financial system so we are we are on
the last
stage of total total perversion of all
kind of
our society all three columns or maybe
four
five columns of the traditional types of
the of the society
uh is disappearing and that is not
only in the united states it is uh in
the world
in the europe and russia as well we
experience the same
we have lost our peasantry during
communism
we are losing now now our soldiers
in uh becoming more and more
sophisticated
exactly as the united states more and
more uh
secure uh behind their their
computers killing computers
killers uh killing computers and uh
maybe we have just a christian orthodox
hierarchy
that tries to fulfill the mission of
this transcendence
that is maybe the the last thing we we
have
we have conserved from from the from the
past
but as well it is very difficult to to
to to be to pretend to believe into
eternity in the world that that
that mocks everybody mocks on
eternity so uh so you should
they should be real heroes these priests
who
uh defend their the faith the
uh their creed their their belief
in god and in eternity in christ
so but i think that is the proof that is
the final
test of of the humanity
how we could defend traditional
values in the anti-totally
anti-traditional
uh medio and anti-traditional ambience
in the situation that is the final test
right so this
this brings the question of course now
if the priests
the warriors the peasants are now
perversions or lost uh and those
are pillars of society what do we
do and what do we do as people as
individuals like what do we do moving
forward
so i i i see no other solution
as to stay uh loyal
to stale to stay
strong defending eternal truths
and we could say in the name of the
eternal truth because
we believe as christians in the eternity
and in the truth
and we could be put as we are
effectively in fact we could be put
in the being
where there is no truth that there is no
eternity only time
and falsification uh but
uh and lie but we that we should not
give up we should not incline we should
fight
for the not for the small part only for
example for the family it's good to
fight for family
but it's not enough it's good to fight
for uh patriotism but it's not enough
we need to to to promote
to stay uh to stay uh
strong defending all the complex
of traditional values that is
more difficult things we should not be
uh specialized for example you defending
family you are defending patriotism we
are defending
christianity you are defending uh
geopolitics
and so we need to unite that we should
be
total total integral men we should
fight for a integral conservation
restoration and revival and reverse
of normality normality human normality
our normality not parts of it so
that was as long as i understand that
was the main failure of the
traditional conservatism they finally
the conservatives
accepted at a certain point
the status quo of the progressives and
they started
they they they they fight on
the new conditions already already
um defined by progressives
so and they uh would say oh
we could not defend the church we just
let us defend the novelty
we could not defend uh peasantry let us
defend
something uh uh man man woman
uh marriage and so we are um we are
giving up our position so we could not
do
but should defend everything not part
everything from the beginning so that is
not about conservatism i prefer to use
the word
the term conservative revolution so we
have
lost so many uh centuries ago the
normality
so we could not just pretend to control
what we
uh yet have uh
we need to restore revival rebuild
re-imagine
recreate we should finally recreate
normality not only save it but
to build it to construct so we should be
proactive
we should be offensive in some way so
we need to promote our our values
in spite of all the wrong image
and we have humanity on our side because
the absolute majority of the humans are
not
ready to uh to uh to be led by a
globalist and to obese
they could not understand the real
proportions the real
meaning of what is going on but
instinctively there are on outside so
we should be brave we should be
offensive we should go
forward uh go ahead as americans uh
say we should go ahead not defend we
should attack
we should install and uh and defend
our values with no no no no
not with thinging of of their demonizing
and
i wish this optimistic vision of the
future
because the eternity as mueller
vandenbrook has said is on
our side huh wonderful
well uh thank you very much sir i have a
million more questions we could talk for
hours longer
uh but we have come up on about two
hours so
uh i would like to wrap this up and just
say thank you very much for
for being open and being willing to
share your ideas and discuss them with
me
i think that there's a lot of common
common ground
um i think that uh there there's
certainly a
vibe in the united states where we're
understanding that
that new isn't always good and the past
isn't always bad and i think that's
something that
we need to focus on and pay more
attention to so
alexander dugan sir i really thank you
very much for your time
uh thank thank you to the audience for
listening uh please follow me on jack
murphy live and check the podcast for
this to be coming out uh
about a day or two uh alexander dugan
sir
thank you very much i hope we have a
chance to do this again
i appreciate it and uh again thank you
thank you it's pleasure bye bye bye